In class, there are lots of
different kinds of people.
Dude, come on.
Those who can make others laugh...
What's that supposed to be?
and those who make things lively.
And I...
If you're gonna be a comedy duo,
you gotta start with an exchange journal!
Why would you think that?
It's obvious, isn't it?
I'm the person holding back laughter off
to the side from the people having fun!
It's no good. I'm going to laugh!
Hey, Nishi-san's laughing!
What? For real?
Am I odd for thinking that?
It's normal, right?
No, it doesn't!
But still!
An exchange diary wouldn't work.
First, you have to deepen
your bond as a duo.
That's why you start an exchange diary!
It's so fast.
The tempo of their
conversation is so fast!
U-Um...
Hey, you're putting
Nishi-san in a tough spot.
Huh?
Sorry!
Oh, no! It's not really...
I killed the mood.
EEEK
That was a shock!
Please don't suddenly bring me
into the conversation!
It isn't that I want to join in!
I'm fine just listening!
But it's creepy that I was smiling
because of what I overheard. I'm sorry!
Nisshi, you really are shy
around people, aren't you?
Hon-chan, where have you been?
Borrowing this book from a friend.
Nisshi, if only you didn't get nervous,
you'd be able to talk normally.
But...
comprehending what other people
are saying is one step.
FULL POWER
VISUALIZATION
Thinking about how
to answer is one more step.
PREPARING
WORDS...
And putting the things that popped
into my mind into words is another step.
Lots of thoughts appear in my head,
but they never come out well in words.
That hurdle is far too high for me!
You're super chatty now, though.
But I don't think it's something
you need to worry about, is it?
I'd say that earlier stuff was more about
enthusiasm than conversation anyway.
I know, but...
I get even more nervous when it's a guy.
Whether they're guys or girls, they bleed
the same color when you stab them.
Please don't stab anyone!
Oh, Hon-chan! Lately, there's a boy
I keep thinking about.
What? When? You're not serious.
Who is it? Who? Who?
Tani-kun, from the class next door.
Who?
Oh!
The person who has library duty with you?
That's right.
You said he doesn't talk much, didn't you?
He isn't the type to talk much.
And yet...
There's nothing to do.
An unexpected sort of student has arrived.
Huh?
Suzuki-san?
They know each other?
YAY YAY YAY
No matter how I look at it,
those two have a strange dynamic!
That's why he's on your mind?
I thought that Tani-kun was like me,
so it was such a shock!
Well, not talking much
doesn't necessarily equal shyness.
She says impolite things so naturally.
And also!
And he wasn't just showing that off!
He's also got delinquents idolizing him!
Huh? Right...
He wasn't scared of them
or just going along with them.
He was talking to delinquents with
a fondly exasperated sort of attitude!
You don't say?
SIGH...
He seems like the protagonist
of a light novel.
NOT
THIS
AGAIN...
He made amusing,
perfectly timed comments,
and I could barely hold my laughter in.
So you were listening to people
and grinning to yourself again?
Nisshi, what if you could just join in?
It's not that I want to participate.
You say that...
but if you can't stop thinking about him,
are you jealous?
What?
Like he's close to being in
the position you want to be in.
I see.
Do you think that's it? That might be it.
I think that's probably it.
YOU AND I ARE POLAR OPPOSITES
So that's what it was.
I've always thought that
I wanted to fix my shyness,
WORDS
AND
THOUGHTS
COMMUNICATION
SKILLS
but the truth is that I wanted to be
included in that boisterous atmosphere!
No, but...
Did you get that?
Oh, I see now!
Perfect.
They're listening to him!
Okay, Tani! Why don't you come
with us and we'll all go to TokyoU?
You're jumping way too far ahead.
He noticed.
What do I do? He noticed that
I laughed just now!
And he's looking this way.
ARGHHHHH...
I'm sorry! I'm sorry that I listened
without permission and laughed! I'm sorry!
Please don't look at me!
It's scary! I'm sorry!
It's totally impossible.
I mean, for some reason,
I'm already terrified!
I feel like people will think, "What?
Why are you laughing? And who are you?"
And they'd be entirely correct, too.
I'm really so very sorry.
Nisshi, let's eat.
Nisshi, what's wrong?
After much consideration,
I think I'll refrain from aiming
too high and stick to my place.
What made you decide that?
AND REALLY,
YOU SHOULD LISTEN
TO THE LECTURE.
Honda!
Oh. Yamada.
Hello.
BOW
'Lo.
That was such a weird response!
Honda, we're using that book
next period. Can I have it?
Oh, sorry! I was going
to give it back later.
Thanks.
Hang on. Don't tell me that
they know each other!
STAAAAARE...
Are you collecting those?
What?
BREAD FESTIVAL
30 PTS IS GUARANTEED A PRIZE!
I was collecting them before, but it's
crazy hard to meet the requirements!
Every day, bread!
EVERY DAY,
BREAD
That's... true.
What did you try for?
The yeti cushion.
It wouldn't suit you.
Yeah, but I want it.
What do I do?
Then, Yamada, do you have
yetis in your room right now?
This is funny!
Yeah.
GASP
I'm so sorry for laughing
at someone else's taste.
AAAAAAAA...
Hey, Yamada!
There's a huge dragonfly loose
in our classroom!
Capture it!
Who summons someone
for something like that?
Hurry up! Hurry up!
See you later!
Bye-bye.
That girl...
Sorry to interrupt your conversation.
Here. Take these.
If you feel sorry, then don't summon me.
Speaking of which, that girl
you were with just now sure is cute!
Huh?
She's just like a doll! I'm so jealous!
Yeah.
She's cute.
Oh! Guys who can honestly
admit stuff like that are popular!
For real? Yay!
Keep it up and catch that dragonfly!
Are you trying to cheer me up?
Huh? When you mentioned delinquents,
you were talking about Yamada?
We were in the same class last year
and he's not a hoodlum or anything.
What, really? Are you sure?
You wouldn't ask some thug to
catch a bug at school, would you?
Hey, wait!
I've got you!
That's true.
His name is Yamada.
Hup. Heave...
Yamada's self-analysis is lacking,
so we bring it to you
through yeti interpretation.
IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
YAY YAY
He's always had a certain trait.
That is...
Huh?
YAMADA (AGE 9)
Honestly, the boys are so dumb.
The teacher will be here soon!
ZIIIIING
He's incredibly drawn to the laugh of
someone he wouldn't expect to laugh!
IN
MIDDLE
SCHOOL
HA
ATHLETIC
NOISY
BOOKISH
QUIET
The further away the person's
character is from his own...
Cut it out! Stop it, you!
BOOKISH QUIET
NOISY ATHLETIC
She laughed!
...the happier he gets when he sees
their hearts have something in common.
SENSE OF HUMOR
"THIS IS FUN!"
"THIS IS FUNNY!"
DAAAAAZED...
He becomes incredibly obsessed
and keeps thinking about them!
TRA LA LA
However, he himself
isn't really aware of this.
LIBRARY
At the library...
You're jumping way too far ahead.
You sound like a crappy customer
asking when his shift is over.
In the classroom...
And by that time...
Yeah.
She's cute.
Though he doesn't know why,
he has already reached the state
where he thinks she's cute!
Hey, Honda, did you watch that movie?
I'm not sure why...
What movie are you talking about?
You know. The one with the music.
But for some reason, he's been
coming to our classroom a lot lately.
Oh, yeah! I saw it!
It was wild, right?
Why?
Crazy, right?
HA HA HA
What?
The conversation's so lively.
Hon-chan looks like
she's having so much fun.
Nishi-san, what music do you like?
I-I don't know much about music.
Um, I think I only listen to old songs.
But I'm not really...
Really?
I'm sorry I can't expand the conversation.
AAAAAAAAA...
Yamada-kun, I know you're being
considerate by trying to include me,
but it just highlights my
terrible conversational skills.
It's painful for me.
It's all right. Nisshi, you can do this!
HAPPY
Yamada basically has no hidden side.
ANGRY
Nisshi, he's the perfect
practice partner for you.
SAD
FUN
That aside...
Yamada, you know...
it's way too obvious
that you're after Nisshi!
Since you don't know each other,
it'd be weird to suddenly talk to her,
so you decided to stick me
in the middle first, right?
The fact that it's so easy
to see makes it hilarious,
* SHE HAS SUCKED HER LIPS ENTIRELY
INSIDE HER MOUTH TO KEEP FROM GRINNING.
but I'm being nice
by not noticing.
Put yourself in my shoes, would you?
Nishi-san, you can have this.
What?
Th-Thank you.
And stop doing that
every time you come here.
Just because you have too little
info on what Nisshi likes
NISHI-SAN
LIKES BREAD
doesn't mean you should bring
bread stickers all the time!
NISHI-SAN IS
COLLECTING
BREAD STICKERS
If I say "this is good" just once,
my grandpa will think it's my favorite.
NISHI-SAN, YOU
CAN HAVE THIS
TH-THANK YOU
He'll buy it for me every time!
You're being just like him!
YAMADA
HONDA'S
GRANDPA
See? Just look at Nisshi.
What do I do?
I mean, the ones with the stickers
on them are better.
And even if I can't collect enough
in time, I don't really mind.
But I can't tell him that now.
That's what her face is saying!
See you later!
Yeah.
You sure get along well.
It's fun listening to the two of you talk.
JUST LISTENING
IS FUN...
Nisshi, you have it all wrong.
NOTICE ALREADY...
But it'll probably take some time
for them to start being friends.
Well now... you will have a lot
of time during summer vacation,
but when you let down your guard,
time disappears before you even notice.
So, take this opportunity to do
things you wouldn't normally do.
Use your time in a meaningful way and
enjoy yourself to your heart's content.
Summer vacation is, after all...
That talk was so long!
YAY
He definitely could've condensed
that speech. Right, Tani?
He repeated the same points several times.
Tani, you really say what
you mean, huh? That's hilarious.
YAY YAY
In our hearts, it feels like it's
already summer vacation, though.
Suzuki...
You have someone, but will you
still hang with us over break?
What? Of course I will!
Where will we go? What'll we do?
Hey, um...
When you want to get
someone's contact info...
how do you ask them?
What? What's this? What's this?
Hold on. Seriously?
I love bittersweet stories like this!
Yamada, has spring come for you?
Even though it's summer?
I'll totally cheer you on!
Well, if it was me...
I'd gauge the mood and take
a photo in the chaos...
then say, "I'll send you the photo later,
so tell me your contact info!"
Did she do that?
Don't pretend to be asleep.
"Suzuki-san, back then,
did you already..."
Don't dub me without consent
and then get angry about it.
What about using an invite
to a game or app as a pretext?
〇〇 MIDDLE SCHOOL 3-〇 GROUP (2)
▢▢▢ HAS LEFT THE GROUP
XXX HAS LEFT THE GROUP
I type messages into a
chat room with no one in it.
△△△ HAS LEFT THE GROUP
Then why do the messages come to me?
Since it's you, Taira, it's fine.
So, I don't count.
Actually...
if you're not close, wouldn't it be scary
to suddenly be asked for contact info?
SERIOUSLY, YOU...
But, I mean...
if a stranger is into you
without you knowing,
and you don't know why,
that's terrifying, right?
Doesn't it make you wonder what they see?
It's just too hard to believe.
You should have more confidence
in who you are now.
It just... doesn't feel right.
I don't think I'm in love
with this person or anything.
REALLY...?
HUH?
I mean, I don't know anything about them.
But I want to know more, so...
How do I put it?
I might be headed toward
falling in love right now!
Full steam ahead!
Just keep heading that way!
I feel much better now.
What? What? What are we so excited about?
It's all so blindingly brilliant.
Sand?
All right! Summer vacation! Charge!
Hey, Nisshi. During summer vacation,
there's a collab cafe for my bias and—
I knew you would come... Yamada!
STAAAARE...
You can do this, Yamada!
It's the last day of first term.
What roundabout method
will you employ today?
Nishi-san.
Nishi-san, I'd like to get
along better with you.
What?
But it's already the start of
summer vacation...
so will you be my friend?
What?
What?! Me?!
A sudden fastball?
I, um...
What do I do?
Instead of making
eye contact and talking,
writing back and forth
might make me less nervous.
Um, then... I'd be happy to.
Yay!
I, um, I'm not good at sophisticated
replies or amusing quips.
Well, it's not like we're becoming
a comedy team, right?
Th-That's true.
But, you know...
the moment you realize
you're headed toward falling in love,
you're already in love, right?
I wonder what the definition
of "love" really is.
Huh? Philosophy?
Tani, where did your love start?
Oh, I was wondering that, too.
I'm not telling you.
30 PTS IS GUARANTEED A PRIZE!
Have I had a little too much fun?
Hello? Tani-kun?
Is now okay to talk?
Yeah, it's fine.
Do you have time tomorrow?
Want to work on our homework together?
Sure, but why are you whispering?
OLDER BROTHER'S ROOM
Oh, um...
Hey, you!
my brother's in the room
next to mine right now, so...
I don't want him
to know about my love life.
BUT SHE WANTS TO
TALK ON THE PHONE
So, tomorrow, let's meet at the library.
All right.
Then, I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah. Good night.
Good night.
What's this?
Do you have cram school today?
No.
I'm going to the library.
Oh.
Take the key with you.
No one will be home later.
FATHER
GOLF
GRANDMA
GRAND GOLF
Okay. I have it.
"I'm going to the library."
Well, that wasn't a lie.
Tani-kun!
I was planning to get here first
and snag us seats,
but we arrived at the same time.
It's fine. You don't
have to do all of that.
KONEKO-MACHI LIBRARY
Huh?
Oh, dear.
KONEKO-MACHI COMMUNITY CENTER
What do we do? There weren't
any open seats anywhere.
And I don't know about waiting around.
Should we look for a cafe
that'll let us hang out?
Was there one around here?
I'm gonna check the map, okay?
Ugh. There's nothing around here.
Suzuki-san.
Want to come to my house?
What?! You don't mind?
THUD THUD
Sure.
It's not very far.
And it's better than finding
a shop in this heat.
His house.
TANI
His house?!
Does that mean his family, too?
FATHER
MOTHER
There's no one home right now anyway.
WHAT?
Since there's no one home,
Suzuki-san won't feel like she has
to be considerate of them.
Huh?
THUD
What?
"THERE'S NO
ONE HOME
RIGHT NOW."
There's no one home?
"THERE'S NO
ONE HOME
RIGHT NOW."
What?!
Please, lead the way!
* DINING ROOM
* STUDYING SERIOUSLY
Of course.
But...
this feels so comfortable.
GROWL...
No, it's...
Should we have lunch?
No, it's just...
GROWL
Hey, Tani-kun?
Are you the type to tell your family
that you're dating someone?
I haven't told them. I don't usually
tell them much about myself.
That's so like you.
Why ask that all of a sudden?
I was just wondering if it's okay for me
to be here, even though it's too late now.
I'm the one who brought you.
Suzuki-san, you don't
have to worry about that.
If you'd prefer,
I'll tell them everything.
No, no! You don't have to follow
my norms for stuff like that!
And every family has
its own boundaries anyway.
MOTHER
COULD PROBABLY
TELL HER...?
FATHER
HMMM...
BROTHER
DEFINITE NO
Let's go at a pace that
won't stress us out, okay?
Yeah.
Thank you for the meal.
THANK YOU
FOR THE MEAL
Well then, shall we resume our studies?
Oh.
I forgot a textbook. I'll go and get it.
Huh? Where? At school?
No. In my room.
Is that all? That's fine then.
"HIS ROOM"
His room?
There's nothing here, though.
This room's so stoic!
DESK
MAT
You like Pokomon?
I used it a fair amount in
elementary school, that's all.
That's so you, Tani-kun!
You take good care of your stuff.
This is one of those ones
that's kind to your back!
My grandma said they're
cheaper as a set,
SHOCK ABSORBING
DISCOUNTED SET
so she gave me one.
It so works!
So, you live with your grandma?
Yeah.
Wow.
You don't have any yearbooks?
Without conversational context?
SHE COULDN'T FIND A MORE
NATURAL WAY TO BRING IT UP
GRADUATION
T-Tani-kun...
Your glasses are different!
TANI
Is it really that surprising?
Tani-kun, your middle school
had a uniform with a high collar,
so it's pretty much the same as
your current one, huh?
I wish I could see you in a blazer.
Really?
Yeah. I want to see lots of things,
and I want to know...
Cat!
Huh?
Oh, you're adorable!
OHHHHH
ADOOOOOORABLE
Pleasure to make your acquaintance.
I've been granted the
honor of dating Tani-kun.
My name is Suzuki.
What are you doing?
Well, I thought I should
formally greet your family.
Right?
Ugh, you're just so cute!
Thank you for having me over.
Tempura-chan, I'll see you later!
Hup!
It's nice that you have a garden!
Be careful where you step.
Hup!
Whoa!
What did I just say?
I'm sorry! I got carried away.
Oh my, oh my, oh my. What's this?
GRIN...
Oh, how naughty.
Hang on.
It isn't like that!
It's a pleasure to meet you!
I attend the same school as Tani-kun!
We're in the same class.
My name is Suzuki!
And, um...
"FRIEND"?
"GIRLFRIEND"?
She's my girlfriend.
Suzuki-san, do you like vegetables?
Yes! I like most foods!
Wait here a moment, then.
I like growing vegetables...
But I just can't use them up fast enough.
If you'd like, you can
take some home with you.
Are you sure?
SO VERY
AVANT-GARDE...!!!
They're odd shapes,
but they are delicious.
Thank you so much!
Come and visit again!
I'm home!
Welcome back.
FIDGET
Mom, um...
someone gave me a bunch of veggies!
Why?
Actually...
You have a boyfriend?
When did that happen?
Please don't tell Dad or my brother.
I won't. I won't say a word.
Bring him by sometime.
What?
Mom, you're in a good mood today.